Register of the Walter Henry Judd papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1923-circa 1982 (Box 32-61)
  - 1948
    - Foreign relations (Box-folder 36: 16)
      - Joint statement by Walter Judd and Brooks Hays relating to the election, October 13
      - "One World--or Two?,", December 1
    - Politics
      - General (Box-folder 37: 1-2)
        Clipping, fragments, notes, and typescripts. Includes radio broadcasts.
      - Republican National Convention (Box-folder 37: 3)
        Typescripts, printed copies, clippings, list, and correspondence. Primarily relates to a speech by Dr. Judd nominating Harold Stassen for President.
      - Radio broadcasts, October-November
  - 1949
    - General
      - Correspondence and clippings (Box-folder 37: 4)
        Includes an exerpt from a speech by Dean Rusk citing Dr. Judd.
      - Debates in the Congressional Record (Box-folder 37: 5)
      - Insertions in the Congressional Record (Box-folder 37: 6)
    - Asia and China
      - General, brief statements (Box-folder 37: 7)
        Typescripts, clipping, and notes. Includes excerpts from an interview by Dr. Judd of Chiang Kai-shek.
      - Interview, January 10
      - "How Can We Aid China?,", January 10
      - Letter to the Editor, China Weekly Review and Shanghai Evening Post and Mercury, January 13-14
      - "Situation in China,", January 24
      - Congressional letter to President Truman, February 7
        Typescripts and correspondence. Includes a response from Dean Acheson.
      - Brief statements, February 12-March 9
      - "Stop the Communists in China or Else,", April
      - Statements in debate relating to aid to China, April 4
      - "Reds Must be Kept from South China," Cedar Rapids Gazette, May 8
        Clipping.
      - Comments on a letter from the Foreign Missions Conference, May
      - "Where and How Can Soviet Expansion be Halted in Asia with Minimum American Cost and Risk?,", July
      - Brief statements, August
        Notes, holographs and typescripts.
      - "The Significance of Events in Asia,", August
      - "Relief of Chinese Students in the United States,", August 1
      - "Speech on the Visit of President Quirino and the Pacific Pact,", August 9
      - Statements on the State Department's White Paper, August 5-21 (Box-folder 37: 8)
        Typescripts, press releases, and clippings. Includes a speech in Congress and a military intelligence report released by Dr. Judd on the Chinese communist movement.
      - Statement on aid to China, August 18 (Box-folder 37: 9)
      - "United States Relations with China,", August 19
      - Statement relating to the China lobby and Chiang Kai-shek, August 25
      - Statement on U.S. policy toward China, October 19
        Typescripts. Includes a copy of a memorandum from John Service to General Stilwell.
      - Congressional statement opposing recognition of communist China, October 20
      - Letter to the Editor, Minneapolis Tribune, and statements relating to the Angus Ward case, November 21-December 5
      - Statements relating to the recognition of communist China, November-December
        Typescripts and a clipping.
      - Statement relating to a trip by Mao Zedong to Moscow, December 18
    - Domestic affairs (Box-folder 38: 1)
      Typescripts, printed copies and fragments. Includes material relating to the economy, housing, and medicine.
    - Foreign relations (Box-folder 38: 2)
      - "America's Expanding International Role,"
      - "Putting All Our Security Eggs in European Basket: A Reckless Gamble,", January 17
      - Statement relating to the Atlantic Pact, March 18
      - Statement on the Foreign Aid Appropriation Bill, 1950 May 26
      - "Which Direction Toward Peace?,", May 29
      - "How Can We Best Resolve Our Differences with Russia?,", May 31
      - "Building the New World,", June 5
      - "Military Aid to Europe and Asia--Why, What, How and to Whom?,", August 17
        Typescript, clipping, and printed copy.
      - "America's New Role in World Affairs,", November 3
  - 1950
    - General
      - Correspondence (including J.W. Fulbright) and citations (Box-folder 38: 3)
      - Debates in Congressional Record (Box-folder 38: 4)
      - Insertions in Congressional Record (Box-folder 38: 5)
    - Asia, Korea and China
      - Notes (Box-folder 38: 6)
      - Untitled statements relating to China, January-February (Box-folder 38: 7)
      - "State Department Alibis for Disaster in China Are Based on Falsehoods,", January
        Typescript and a printed copy of a related statement.
      - Statements on diplomatic recognition and admission of communist China to the United Nations, January-July
        Typescripts, notes, and a radio broadcast transcript.
      - "Remarks on the Bill to Provide Economic Aid to the Republic of Korea,", January 19
        Typescript, printed copies, and notes.
      - "What Should United States Policy in China Be?,", January 30
      - Response to a New York Times article relating to State Department policy toward China, March 17
      - "What Should United States Policy Be in Asia?,", March 26-28
      - Statement on the United Nations, April 3
        Typescript and a letter from Matthew Woll of the Free Trade Union Committee.
      - "What is the Meaning of the Korean Invasion for the United States and the United Nations?,", June 27 (Box-folder 38: 8)
        Typescripts, printed copies, and correspondence (including H.H. Kung).
      - "Attack on Korea,", June 27 (Box-folder 38: 9)
      - "Comments on the Korean Crisis,", June 28
      - "How and Why Did We Get into War in Korea?,", July 18
        Printed copy, proofs, letter, and miscellany.
      - Brief statements on Korea, July-September
        Printed copies, typescripts, clippings, and notes.
      - "The Meaning of Korea to You,", August 21
      - "Autopsy: Our Blunders in Asia,", Autumn
      - Statement regarding the Korean Crisis, September 15
      - "What Now in China?,", October
      - "Disaster in China," Catholic Digest, October
      - Statement relating to Formosa, December 1
      - Congressional letter to President Truman, December 5
      - Statement, December 8
      - Congratulatory statement relating to Burmese independence day, December 20
      - "The Five Lies,", circa December
    - Foreign relations
      - "Is the Kremlin's Aim Conquest of the U.S.A.?,", January 17 (Box-folder 39: 1)
        Printed copy, typescript, and correspondence.
      - Joint statement (with Brooks Hays) relating to House Concurrent Resolution 64, January 31 (Box-folder 39: 2)
      - Statement relating to the CARE book bill, March 1
      - Memorandum of conversation with the British Ambassador, March 18
      - "Should We Cut the Appropriation for the Marshall Plan?,", March 28
      - Statements relating to the foreign aid program, March 29, 31
      - Statement relating to communism, April 4
      - Joint statement (with Brooks Hays) relating to House Concurrent Resolution 64, April 6
        Printed copy and letter.
      - "Which Way to Freedom and Peace?,", May 8
      - Broadcast relating to the Mutual Security Program, May 10
      - Broadcast relating to the World Health Organization, June 12
        Typescripts and letter.
      - "Transfers of Naval Vessels,", June 1
        Printed copy and typescript.
      - Statements, June 15-August 18
      - "The Issues of Our Time," Christian-Evangelist, August 23
      - Statement, August 26
      - "The Fourteen Questions,", September 1
      - "Lippmann's Defense Theory," Minneapolis Tribune, September 9
        Clippings, note, and typescript.
      - Joint statement (with Brooks Hays) relating to House Concurrent Resolution 64, September 18
      - "Christian Foundation Stones," Wesley News, November 17
    - Domestic affairs (Box-folder 39: 3)
      Typescripts and printed copies. Includes material relating to Dean Acheson, Alger Hiss, the State Department, housing, communism, and civil rights.
    - Politics (Box-folder 39: 4-6)
      Correspondence, printed material, and typescripts. Includes a report on the 81st Congress.
  - 1951
    - General
      - Correspondence and clippings (Box-folder 39: 7)
      - Debates in the Congressional Record (Box-folder 39: 8)
      - Insertions in the Congressional Record (Box-folder 39: 9)
      - Just Between Us (Box-folder 39: 10-11)
        Includes newsletter, correspondence, typescripts, radio broadcasts, and notes.
    - Asia and China
      - "What Are We to Believe about Asia?,", January (Box-folder 40: 1)
      - Statements relating to Korea, Formosa, and China, January 3-15
      - Joint statement relating to a proposed Pacific Pact, January 23
        Press release and clipping.
      - Speech relating to China, January 30
      - "What Lies Behind Korea?,", February 11
      - "Does China Mean World War III?,", March 13
      - "What Should We Do about Asia?,", April 6
      - Statements relating to the dismissal of General MacArthur, April 11-19
      - "What Shall We Do in Asia?," Credit and Financial Management, June
      - Article on Korea, June 19 (Box-folder 40: 2)
        Correspondence and fragments of clippings.
      - Statement on Korea, June 27 (Box-folder 40: 3)
      - Interview relating to Korea, June 30
      - "U.S. Perimeter in Asia," Catholic Digest, July
      - Press release, July 13
      - Statements relating to the Philippine Security Treaty, August
      - "Why Should We Be Fighting in Korea?,", August 23
        Printed copy and typescripts.
      - Speech notes, October 9
    - Domestic affairs (Box-folder 40: 4)
      Typescripts and printed copies.
    - Foreign relations (Box-folder 40: 5)
      - "We Must Move to Get a Stronger World Organization,", January
      - Newsletters issued by the Committee on World Freedom (written by Dr. Judd?), January-April
      - Statement relating to Korea and communism, January 3
      - Congressional letter to President Truman relating to India, January 30
      - Speech relating to foreign aid, February 9
        Newsletter.
      - Statement relating to French President Vincent Auriol, April 2
      - "Building Unity in a Divided World,", May 17
      - "Security Comes First," Rotarian, June
      - Statement relating to the Council of Europe, June 28
      - Statements relating to the Mutual Security Act of 1951, August 16-17
      - "Why Give Aid for Refugees into Israel?,", August 17
      - Speech, August 25
      - Congressional letter to Dean Acheson relating to the United Nations, November 11
  - 1952
    - General
      - Correspondence and clippings (Box-folder 40: 6)
      - Debates in the Congressional Record (Box-folder 40: 7)
      - Insertions in the Congressional Record (Box-folder 40: 8)
      - Just Between Us (Box-folder 40: 9-10)
        Includes newsletters, correspondence, typescripts, and radio broadcasts.
    - Asia and China (Box-folder 40: 11)
      - Statement relating to the Korean War and the presidential campaign
      - Letter to the Editor, Minneapolis Star-Tribune, February-March
      - "What is the Role of the New Japan?,", March 16
      - Letters to the Editor and statements relating to Dr. Judd's involvement in the China Lobby, April-May
        Typescripts and printed copies. Includes a response to a column by Drew Pearson.
      - Speech notes, April 2
      - "Korean Prisoners of War and Truce Talks,", April 10
      - "POWs Must be Protected," Washington Post, April 21
      - Press release summary of a radio broadcast, June 4
      - Statement on the Philippines, December 13
    - Domestic affairs (Box-folder 40: 12)
      Typescripts and printed copies. Includes material relating to compulsory health insurance and universal military training.
    - Foreign relations (Box-folder 40: 13)
      - "Mutual Security Act of 1952,", May 23
      - "Education for America's New Role in World Affairs,", June 21
      - Speech on foreign policy, October 6
    - Politics
      - General (Box-folder 41: 1)
        Notes, clippings, broadcast transcripts, typescripts, and printed copies. Relates to Dr. Judd's congressional campaign and the presidential election. Includes a draft of a speech written for Dwight Eisenhower and multiple drafts of minutes of a meeting with Dwight Eisenhower and his advisors.
      - Republican National Convention (Box-folder 41: 2)
        Variations of a speech, short statements, and correspondence.
  - Statehood for Alaska and Hawaii, 1952-1958 (Box-folder 41: 3)
    Typescripts, notes, correspondence (including Felix Stump), and printed matter. Includes material relating to communism in Hawaii.
  - 1953
    - General
      - Clipping and a program (Box-folder 41: 4)
      - Debates in the Congressional Record (Box-folder 41: 5)
      - Insertions in the Congressional Record (Box-folder 41: 6)
      - Just Between Us (Box-folder 42: 1, Box-folder 41: 7)
        Includes newsletter, typescripts, correspondence, and radio broadcasts. Includes material relating to Korean POWs.
    - Asia, Korea and China (Box-folder 42: 2)
      - General, 1951-1963
        Clippings, notes, brief typescripts, and a Letter to the Editor. Includes a statement on Korean truce.
      - "China Must Not Be Traded for North Korea"
      - "Outlook for the Free World in Asia,", May 2-June 30
      - Broadcast relating to Indochina, May 14
      - Reports relating to the recognition of Communist China, July
    - Domestic affairs (Box-folder 42: 3)
      Typescripts and printed copies. Includes material relating to defense appropriations and government reorganization.
    - Foreign relations (Box-folder 42: 4)
      - Statement on the death of Josef Stalin, March 6
      - Statements in debate on foreign aid, March 30
      - "The World Crisis and Its Hope," Church Herald, June 6
      - "Why Should We Extend the Mutual Security Program?,", June 18
      - Press release relating to the sale of surplus agricultural commodities, June 26
  - 1954
    - General
      - Clippings (Box-folder 42: 5)
      - Debates in the Congressional Record (Box-folder 42: 6)
      - Insertions in the Congressional Record (Box-folder 42: 7)
        Includes correspondence with Thruston B. Morton and others.
      - Just Between Us and other programs (Box-folder 42: 8-9)
        Radio broadcasts, correspondence and transcripts.
    - Asia and China
      - General (Box-folder 43: 1)
        Brief statements, interview, and notes.
      - "Why Mao's Government Threatens World Peace," U.S. News and World Report, January-February (Box-folder 43: 2)
        Printed copy, press release, and correspondence (including Joseph Grew and J. Leighton Stuart).
      - Statement relating to Indochina, February 18 (Box-folder 43: 3)
      - "China and U.S.-Asian Policy,", March 9
      - "The Free World's Stake in Asia,", March 17
      - "First-Hand Report on Asia,", March 26
      - "What Should We Do about Asia?,", May 7
      - "The Significance for Foreign Trade of Communist Conquests in Asia,", May 19
        Typescript, printed copy, and correspondence.
      - "Should We Trade with the Soviet Union and Communist China?,", May 28
      - "President Magsaysay's Administration,", May 20
      - "Comments on the Indochina Munich,", July 20
        Typescripts and notes.
      - Interview, July 31
      - "The Case Against Recognition of Communist China,", August 20
    - Domestic affairs (Box-folder 43: 4)
      Typescripts, printed copy, notes, and clippings. Includes material relating to Indian health services, agricultural surpluses, and the Wolf Ladejinsky loyalty-security case.
    - Foreign relations (Box-folder 43: 5)
      - Brief statement on the Berlin conference, February
        Typescript and clipping.
      - "Pakistan's Food Shortage Relieved By Only Two-Thirds of American Wheat Grant,", March 17
        Printed copy, typescripts, and a press release.
      - Statement on the sale of agricultural surpluses, May 10
      - Radio broadcast relating to Central America and Indochina, May 30
      - "Free World at the Crossroads,", June 17 and December
        Typescripts, printed copy, notes, and correspondence.
      - Congressional letter to President Eisenhower in response to a statement by Anthony Eden, June 24
      - "Mutual Security Act of 1954,", June 29
      - Press release relating to the shooting-down of an airliner over Indochina, July 24
      - Statement, August 20
      - Press release relating to a European treaty ratification, December 30
    - Politics (Box-folder 43: 6)
      Press releases, typescripts, miscellany, and correspondence.
  - 1955
    - General
      - Correspondence and clippings (Box-folder 43: 7)
      - Debates in the Congressional Record (Box-folder 43: 8)
      - Insertions in the Congressional Record (Box-folder 43: 9)
        Includes correspondence.
      - Just Between Us (Box-folder 44: 1)
        Typescripts and correspondence relating to radio broadcasts.
    - Asia and China
      - General (Box-folder 44: 2)
        Brief statements, notes, and clippings. Includes notes relating to communications (?) with John Foster Dulles.
      - "Why We Cannot Let the Communists Have Formosa,", January 25 (Box-folder 44: 3)
      - Press releases relating to China, March-July
      - "Are We Right or Wrong in Asia?,", July 10
      - Statement of the House Committee on Foreign Affairs, Far East Subcommittee, on recognition of China, August 1
      - "One of the Great Underdeveloped Resources in the Orient: Millions of English-Speaking Asians,", August 2
      - "What Is the Meaning of the Current Talks with Red China?,", August 7
        Radio broadcast transcript and letters.
    - Domestic affairs (Box-folder 44: 4)
      Printed copies, typescripts, and press releases. Includes material relating to taxes and wage increases.
    - Foreign relations (Box-folder 44: 5)
      - "Our Christian Task in Today's World,", February 25
      - "The Christian Approach to Solving World Problems,", March 7
      - "Message for Seventh Anniversary of Jewish State,", April 27
        Notes, typescript, and letter.
      - "What Must We Do to Prevent War?,", June 29
      - "America's Book Program Abroad Is Making Good Headway,", June 30
      - Press releases relating to proposed peace talks, June-July
      - Press release relating to foreign aid, July 12
      - Open letter to President Eisenhower, July 14
      - Press release relating to the sale of agricultural surpluses, July 25
      - "USO,", September
        Brief statement and letter.
  - Foreign aid, 1955-1964 (Box-folder 44: 6)
    Speech notes and printed material.
  - Captive nations, 1955-1979 (Box-folder 44: 7)
    Notes, typescripts, and miscellany.
  - 1956
    - General
      - Debates in the Congressional Record (Box-folder 44: 8)
      - Insertions in the Congressional Record (Box-folder 44: 9)
      - Just Between Us (Box-folder 45: 1-2, Box-folder 44: 10)
        Includes newsletters, typescripts, radio broadcasts, and correspondence.
    - Asia and China (Box-folder 45: 3)
      - General
        Brief statements, typescripts, printed copies, notes, clippings, and correspondence.
      - "KEEP: Rural Development in Japan,", March 29
      - Statement relating to the admission of China to the United Nations, July 18
      - "The Outlook in Asia,", July 27
    - Domestic affairs (Box-folder 45: 4)
      Printed copies and press releases. Includes material relating to labor, aviation, education, and economic policy.
    - Foreign relations (Box-folder 45: 5)
      Includes Asia and China.
      - "A Reappraisal of Goals and Methods in 'Foreign Aid'"
      - Statements relating to the World Health Organization, February-October
        Typescripts and draft resolution.
      - "International Tensions,", April 30
      - "A Congressman Looks Inside the State Department," U.S. News and World Report, May 31
      - "How to Meet the Communist 'Peace' Offensive,", June 6
      - "Mutual Security Act of 1956,", June-July
        Printed copies of statements in debate.
      - "How Important is Foreign Aid?,", June 10
    - Politics (Box-folder 45: 6)
      Notes, printed copy, and typescripts. Includes material relating to Richard Nixon, Dwight Eisenhower, and a reply to Dr. Judd.
  - 1957
    - General
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 45: 7)
      - Debates in the Congressional Record (Box-folder 45: 8)
      - Insertions in the Congressional Record (Box-folder 45: 9)
      - Just Between Us (Box-folder 45: 10-11)
        Notes, typescripts, and clippings relating to radio broadcasts.
    - Asia and China (Box-folder 46: 1)
      Notes, brief statements, interview, book review, and miscellany.
    - Domestic affairs (Box-folder 46: 2)
      Printed copies and typescripts.
    - Foreign relations (Box-folder 46: 3)
      - Press release relating to the Middle East, February 21
      - Statements on foreign aid, circa March
      - "How Effective Is Our Foreign Aid Program?,", March 31
      - "Our Foreign Aid Program--A Bureaucratic Nightmare," Readers Digest, April
        Printed copy and correspondence.
      - "Primary Aim of Foreign Aid Is to Help the United States,", April
      - "What About the Foreign Aid Program?,", May 6
      - "What Shall We Do about 'Foreign Aid?,'", July 16
      - "Towards a Happier Neighborhood,", October
      - Interview relating to foreign aid, October 22
      - Statement to the United Nations relating to Korea, November 12
  - 1958
    - General
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 46: 4)
      - Debates in the Congressional Record (Box-folder 46: 5)
      - Insertions in the Congressional Record (Box-folder 46: 6)
    - Asia and China (Box-folder 46: 7)
      Notes, clippings, and a short statement.
    - Domestic affairs (Box-folder 46: 8)
      Typescripts, clippings, press releases, and printed copies. Includes material relating to education and labor.
    - Foreign relations (Box-folder 46: 9)
      - General
        Notes and brief statements.
      - "Two Worlds in Deadly Conflict," Faith at Work
      - "Economic Development of Underdeveloped Countries," Department of State Bulletin, January
      - "Our Heritage," Bulletin of the Crozer Theological Seminary, January
      - "World Issues and the Christian,", January 5
      - "Mutual Security Act of 1958,", May 13
      - "The Conflict Moves Toward a Climax,", June 8
      - Statement on the sale of agricultural surpluses, circa July
        Typescript, printed copy and a letter.
      - "The World Situation Demands United Action by all Christians,", September 11-14
  - Statements relating to John Foster Dulles and Christian Herter, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 46: 10)
    Typescripts, printed copies, and press releases.
  - 1959
    - General
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 46: 11)
      - Debates in the Congressional Record (Box-folder 46: 12)
      - Insertions in the Congressional Record (Box-folder 46: 13)
        Includes a letter.
      - Just Between Us (Box-folder 46: 14)
        Newsletters.
    - Asia and China
      - General (Box-folder 46: 15)
      - "Should We Establish Diplomatic and Commercial Relations with Communist China and Admit it [to] Membership in the United Nations?,", March 19 (Box-folder 46: 16)
      - "Against Seating of Communist China in the United Nations,", August 17
    - Domestic affairs (Box-folder 47: 1)
      Printed copies, press releases, and typescripts. Includes material relating to labor and education.
    - Foreign relations
      - General
        - Statement on exchange programs (Box-folder 47: 2)
        - Statements relating to a resolution on Panama, February 2
        - Statement relating to the Berlin crisis and John Foster Dulles, March 5
          Press release.
        - "Where Do We Stand Now in Our World Relations,", March 9